Guide to the Media Entertainment, Inc. Oral History Collection ALBA.074
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Media Entertainment, Inc. Oral History Collection
1996
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Media Entertainment, Inc.
ALBA.074
1.25 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box
20 VHS
Consists of videos and transcripts for eleven interviews conducted in 1996 for the documentary In Search of The Lincoln Brigade (circa 1999).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Historical Note
The Abraham Lincoln Brigade were volunteers from the United States that went to Spain to fight fascism in the Spanish Civil War. The documentary In Search of The Lincoln Brigade, produced by Media Entertainment, Inc., recounts the Spanish Civil War through the eyes of eleven Abraham Lincoln Brigade volunteers.
Custodial History
The Media Entertainment, Inc. Oral History Collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access DVDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Scope and Contents
Consists of videos and transcripts for eleven interviews conducted in 1996 for the documentary In Search of the Lincoln Brigade (circa 1999). The interviewees are: Morris Brier, Ralph Fasanella, Milt Felsen, Harry Fisher, Moe Fishman, Leonard Levenson, Abe Smorodin, Bill Susman, Anthony Toney, Bill Van Felix, and Milt Wolff.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American -- Interviews.; Interviews.; Transcripts.; Videocassettes.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American
- Morris Briar, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 1)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Briar)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Ralph Fasanella, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 2-4)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Fasanella)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Milt Felsen, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 5)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Felsen)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Harry Fisher, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 6)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Fishman)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Moe Fishman, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 7-9)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Fishman)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Len Levenson, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Vhs 10-12)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Levenson)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Abe Smorodin, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Vhs 13-15)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Smorodin)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Bill Susman, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Vhs 16)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Susman)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Anthony Toney, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Vhs 17)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Toney)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Bill Van Felix, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Vhs 18-19)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Van Felix)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Milt Wolff, 1996
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Vhs 20)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Dvd Wolff)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder 11)